<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science on Chris Bailey, PhD, CSCS*D, RSCC</title>
    <link>/tags/data-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Science on Chris Bailey, PhD, CSCS*D, RSCC</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/data-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Variability and Measure Magnitude in Performance Data</title>
      <link>/post/variability-and-measure-magnitude-in-performance-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/variability-and-measure-magnitude-in-performance-data/</guid>
      <description>Getting started with monitoring data The data Heteroscedasticity Start visually  Add in some statistics Practical Application   Getting started with monitoring data Initially, we shoud be primarily concerned with reliability. Like me, you probably pick assessments that have shown to be reliable and valid previously in research. But, you should also continuously evaluate your own reliability. If you are completing your own analysis and producing your own visualizations in R, you can build this into your code somewhat easily.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making sense of student evaluations: A data science/text mining approach</title>
      <link>/post/making-sense-of-student-evaluations-a-data-science-text-mining-approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/making-sense-of-student-evaluations-a-data-science-text-mining-approach/</guid>
      <description>After every semester I find myself in the same situation, reading through student evaluations and comments trying to find some value in them. The quantitative section may be seemingly straightforward, with higher values being better, but they are often compared to and normalized to other courses that are completely different from yours. But at least they are objective. I usually struggle the most with the comments section.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>