<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chris Bailey, PhD, CSCS*D, RSCC</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Chris Bailey, PhD, CSCS*D, RSCC</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Wireless Technology for Monitoring and Improving Performance in S&amp;C: Part 1 Athlete Monitoring Basics</title>
      <link>/post/wireless-technology-for-monitoring-and-improving-performance-in-s-c-part-1-athlete-monitoring-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/wireless-technology-for-monitoring-and-improving-performance-in-s-c-part-1-athlete-monitoring-basics/</guid>
      <description>Objectives Why Wireless? Athlete Monitoring? What Athlete Monitoring is not… Why monitor? Conclusion (for part 1)   The following post comes from an adaptation of a talk I gave at the NSCA Nebraska State Clinic back in January.
Objectives  Learn basic athlete monitoring techniques (part 1) Learn about current technology that can be applied to S&amp;amp;C as well as other sport performance areas (part 2) Learn about pitfalls and issues associated with these methods (part 2) Be able to incorporate the previous objectives to produce data-driven justifications for making training and sport performance decsisions   Why Wireless?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Variability and Measure Magnitude in Performance Data</title>
      <link>/post/variability-and-measure-magnitude-in-performance-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/variability-and-measure-magnitude-in-performance-data/</guid>
      <description>Getting started with monitoring data The data Heteroscedasticity Start visually  Add in some statistics Practical Application   Getting started with monitoring data Initially, we shoud be primarily concerned with reliability. Like me, you probably pick assessments that have shown to be reliable and valid previously in research. But, you should also continuously evaluate your own reliability. If you are completing your own analysis and producing your own visualizations in R, you can build this into your code somewhat easily.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making sense of student evaluations: A data science/text mining approach</title>
      <link>/post/making-sense-of-student-evaluations-a-data-science-text-mining-approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/making-sense-of-student-evaluations-a-data-science-text-mining-approach/</guid>
      <description>After every semester I find myself in the same situation, reading through student evaluations and comments trying to find some value in them. The quantitative section may be seemingly straightforward, with higher values being better, but they are often compared to and normalized to other courses that are completely different from yours. But at least they are objective. I usually struggle the most with the comments section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bat Swing GRF Part 2: Analysis in R</title>
      <link>/post/bat-swing-grf-part-2-analysis-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/bat-swing-grf-part-2-analysis-in-r/</guid>
      <description>Prior to analysis, these trials have already been cleaned. By that I mean that only the force production necessary for this movement are present in the data. There is no blank space or data with the athletes simply standing on the force plate. As a result of that, the analysis is much easier, but the force values of each force plate cannot be summed since the time has been altered (trimmed at the beginning or the end).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bat Swing Ground Reaction Forces Part 1</title>
      <link>/post/bat-swing-ground-reaction-forces-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/bat-swing-ground-reaction-forces-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Similarities in Force-Time Curves Monitoring of jumping ground reaction force (GRF), especially in the vertical direction (vGRF) is becoming more common these days with more affordable force plate options and software. If you are willing to learn and put in the effort, you can design your own force-time curve analysis programs in R or python and avoid the budget hit. Matt Sams created an open source vertical jump analysis project for this purpose, coded in R with a shiny app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/search/placeholder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/search/placeholder/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/top/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/top/about/</guid>
      <description>Chris Bailey, PhD, CSCS*D, RSCC Chris Bailey is a Clinical Assistant Professor in the Kinesiology, Health Promotion, and Recreation Department at the University of North Texas. He is a Certified Strength and Conditioning Specialist (CSCS) and a Registered Strength and Conditioning Coach (RSCC) through the National Strength and Conditioning Association (NSCA).
At UNT, Chris teaches courses in athlete monitoring, biomechanics, quantitative analysis, quantitative procedures, strength and conditioning, and exercise test and prescription.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>